Guide to the Mabel Loomis Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1881-1932; Series V; 6.25 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Unpublished Writings
    - "The Great Blizzard of '88," AMS and TMS, 1889 (Box 77, Folder 309)
    - "Friendly Enemies," AMS, 1889 (Box 77, Folder 310)
    - "Suggestions for Amateur Observers," AMS, 1889 (Box 77, Folder 311)
    - "Village Improvement," AMS, [1880s] (Box 78, Folder 312)
    - "The Evolution of a Style," AMS and TMS, 1890 (Box 78, Folder 313)
    - Introduction to an article on the identity of Saxe Holm, TMS and correspondence, 1890 (Box 78, Folder 314)
    - Memorial to Mrs. Stearns, AMS, 1893 (Box 78, Folder 315)
    - "The Province of the Novel," AMS, 1895 (Box 78, Folder 316)
    - "All About the Ruddy Planet," AMS and TMS, 1895-1896 (Box 78, Folder 317)
    - "A Race with an Arizona Cloud Burst," TMS and AMS, 1896 (Box 78, Folder 318)
    - Short resume of an eclipse expedition, AMS, 1896 (Box 78, Folder 319)
    - "Molokai," AMS, [post-1896] (Box 78, Folder 320)
    - Essay on Boxford, AMS, [pre-1897] (Box 78, Folder 321)
    - Essay on the Yerkes Observatory, AMS, 1898 November (Box 78, Folder 322)
    - Greek mythology, AMS, [late 1890s] (Box 78, Folder 323)
    - A play, AMS, [1880s-1890s] (Box 78, Folder 324)
    - "One Week in July, (Story in Four Parts)," Part I, AMS, [1880-1899] (Box 78, Folder 325)
    - Biographical note on Emily Dickinson, 10 Pages AMS and TMS, 1900 (Box 78, Folder 326)
    - "Old Amherst," AMS, 1900 (Box 78, Folder 327)
    - Essay on Mabel Loomis Todd's observations on nature, AMS, 1900 (Box 78, Folder 328)
    - "Where Summer Never Ends," AMS, 1901 April 27 (Box 78, Folder 329)
    - "Running Amok," AMS, 1901 June 30 (Box 78, Folder 330)
    - "Three Unique Weddings," AMS and correspondence, 1901 (Box 78, Folder 331)
    - "The Longest Eclipse Ever Observed," AMS, 1901 (Box 78, Folder 332)
    - "Siam and the Siamese," AMS, 1901 (Box 78, Folder 333)
    - The beginning of a Filipino play, AMS, 1901 (Box 78, Folder 334)
    - The Junior Prom, AMS, [early 1900s] (Box 78, Folder 335)
    - Essay on Yosemite Valley, AMS, 1902 May 15 (Box 78, Folder 336)
    - Another Eclipse Trip to Tripoli, AMS, 1904-1905 (Box 78, Folder 337)
    - Multum in Parvo, AMS and TMS, [pre-1905] (Box 78, Folder 338)
    - The Heritage, TMS, [pre-1905] (Box 79, Folder 339)
    - "The Gift of Kono-Hana-Sakuya-Hime," TMS and AMS, [pre-1905] (Box 79, Folder 340)
    - "A Commonplace Story," AMS and TMS, [pre-1905] (Box 79, Folder 341)
    - "Arts and Crafts in Tripoli," AMS, 1905 (Box 79, Folder 342)
    - "From Desert to Jungle in Search of Eclipses," AMS, 1905 (Box 79, Folder 343)
    - Play about an astronomical expedition to the desert, AMS, 1905 (Box 79, Folder 344)
    - Book review of Arthur W. Clayden's Cloud Studies, AMS, [post-1905] (Box 79, Folder 345)
    - "Tripoli of the Sahara," AMS and TMS, [post-1905] (Box 79, Folder 346)
    - "Sunny Seville," AMS and TMS, 1906 (Box 79, Folder 347)
    - "Our Nation's Portal: Ellis Island," AMS, 1906 (Box 79, Folder 348)
    - "The Nitrate Wealth of Tarapacá"
      - AMS, 1907 (Box 79, Folder 349)
      - TMS and correspondence, 1907 (Box 79, Folder 350)
    - "Peru and Progress," AMS, 1908 (Box 79, Folder 351)
    - Mabel Loomis Todd's notes taken during a balloon flight, AMS, 1910 May 6 (Box 79, Folder 352)
    - Essay and notes on Halley's Comet, AMS, 1910 (Box 79, Folder 353)
    - Notes on protecting almond trees from frost, AMS, 1911-1913 (Box 79, Folder 354)
    - "Our Neighbors," AMS and TMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 355)
    - Beginning of story of overtaking a carriage, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 356)
    - "Meteors," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 357)
    - "Indians and Art," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 358)
    - "Lily Dance," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 359)
    - "The History of Astronomy," chapters II and III, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 360)
    - "Story of Margaret," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 361)
    - "The Prisoner of Pampa," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 362)
    - "Farce," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 363)
    - Essay on Japan, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 364)
    - Story on Celia Day, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 365)
    - "British Museum Notes on Carthage," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 366)
    - Essay on the Ray Memorial in Franklin, Massachusetts, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 367)
    - "Amherst College Today," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 368)
    - Notes on sweet peas, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 369)
    - Short unpublished material, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 370)
    - Notes by Mabel Loomis Todd on flowers accompanied by poems of Alice Ward Bailey, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 371)
    - "Roses Have Thorns," play in five acts
      - AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 372)
      - TMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 373)
    - "The Astronomer," play in four acts
      - AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 80, Folder 374)
      - TMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 375)
    - Notes by Mabel Loomis Todd and David P. Todd for an astronomy reader, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 376)
    - "Silhouettes of a Year," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 377)
    - "A Long Look Backward," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 378)
    - "Of Them That Speak Lies," AMS and TMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 379)
    - Notes on one hundred great astronomers, AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 380)
    - "Gounod," AMS, [pre-1913] (Box 81, Folder 381)
    - "Cry of the Loon," TMS, [post-1913] (Box 81, Folder 382)
    - Writings of others copied by Mabel Loomis Todd, AMS, [post-1913] (Box 81, Folder 383)
    - "Report of the Nizamiah Observatory," AMS, 1916-1917 (Box 81, Folder 384)
    - "Alongside the Everglades," TMS, 1918 February (Box 81, Folder 385)
    - "En Route"
      - Notes, AMS, [early 1920s] (Box 81, Folder 386)
      - TMS, [early 1920s] (Box 81, Folder 387)
    - "Life of Mary Barr Munroe," TMS, 1921 (Box 82, Folder 388)
    - Christmas lists, 1922-1931 (Box 82, Folder 389)
    - "The Story of Emily Dickinson's Letters," TMS and correspondence, 1930 (Box 82, Folder 390)
    - Review of Hugh Walpole's Rogue Herries, MS, 1932 (Box 82, Folder 391)
    - A fictional account of a Spanish attack on New York City, Undated (Box 81, Folder 392)
    - Unpublished book reviews, AMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 393)
    - Notes on famous women, TMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 394)
    - Scattered notes on astronomy, AMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 395)
    - Notes on Turner's "Fighting Temeraire," AMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 396)
    - Poetry selections chosen by Mabel Loomis Todd for a yearbook, AMS and TMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 397)
    - Miscellaneous short literary pieces, AMS and TMS, Undated (Box 81, Folder 398)
    - Notes on domestic arrangements: recipes, Undated (Box 81, Folder 399)
    - Notes on domestic arrangements: menus, lists, calendars, etc., Undated (Box 82, Folder 400)
    - Lists of photographs used by Mabel Loomis Todd, Undated (Box 82, Folder 401)
    - Mabel Loomis Todd's notes on Lavinia Dickinson's remarks, AMS TMS, Undated (Box 82, Folder 402)
    - Literary notes, AMS, Undated (Box 82, Folder 403)
    - Miscellaneous literary notes, AMS, Undated (Box 82, Folder 404-407)
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 82, Folder 408-414)
    - Fragments, AMS, Undated (Box 82, Folder 415)
- Scrapbooks, 1871-1932; Series VI; 4.25 linear feet (9 boxes)
  SCRAPBOOKS is arranged in the order in which Mabel Loomis Todd compiled them, which is roughly chronological.
  - Personal
    - Volume I (No. 2), 1871-1896 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Volume II (No. 5), 1895-1899 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Volume III (No. 7), 1900-1903 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Volume IV (No. 8), 1904-1907 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Volume V (No. 12), 1908 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Volume VI (No. 13), 1909-1910 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Volume VII (No. 15), 1911-1916 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Volume X (No. 18), 1920-1921 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Volume XI (No. 20), 1922-1923 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Volume XII (No. 21), 1924 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Volume XIII (No. 22), 1925-1926 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Volume XIV (No. 23), 1826-1830 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - (No. 1), 1863 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - (Fairhaven, Massachusetts (No. 11), 1906-1913 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Cruise of Aloha, Trip Around the World (231 days), Arthur Curtiss James (No. 19), 1921-1922 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - "As to Friends", 1891-1930 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Scraps, "Methods Illustrated", Undated (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Published articles
      - No. 4, 1892-1905 (Box 91, Folder 18)
      - No. 10, 1906-1907 (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - Death in Maine (no. 25)
      See: box 112, folder 393.
- Subject Files, 1865-1932; Series VII; 9.25 linear feet (25 boxes)
  SUBJECT FILES has ten sections.
  Persons is arranged alphabetically.
  William Austin Dickinson is arranged by type of material (i. e., letters of William Austin Dickinson to Mabel Loomis Todd, notebooks, essay, etc.)
  Clubs is arranged alphabetically by club or organization.
  Wedding and Anniversaries is chronologically arranged.
  Sickness and Death is arranged by family member: Eben Jenks Loomis, Mary Alden Loomis, and Mabel Loomis Todd.
  Social Life is arranged by type of material (i.e. newspaper clippings, invitations, etc.).
  Art is chronologically arranged.
  Music is chronologically arranged.
  Biographical Writings has three parts: genealogical materials, biographical materials, and autobiographical materials.
  - Persons
    - Alcott, Louisa May (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Alcott family (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Caroline Lovejoy (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Andrews, John A. (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Benedict, Commodore E.C. (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Cable, George W. (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Child, Edwin Burrage (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Compton, Naomi Todd (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Coonley, Prentiss (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Cowles, Emma M. (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Crawford, Harriet Cutler (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Cunnigham, Abigail (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Cutter, Harriet W. (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - D (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Dickinson, Emily (poems set to music, 1896) (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Dickinson, William Austin (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Eastman, Charles A. (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Emerson, Mary Moody (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Fairchild, David (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Fairchild, Marian (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Field, Kate (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - G (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - Gardner, Eugene C. (Box 92, Folder 20)
    - Gardner, F. N. (Box 92, Folder 20)
    - Glidden, Etta H. (Box 92, Folder 21)
    - Graham, Margaret T. (Box 92, Folder 22)
    - Grosvenor, Prof. Edwin (Box 92, Folder 23)
    - Hayne, Paul H. (Box 92, Folder 24)
    - Head, Franklin H. and family (Box 92, Folder 25)
    - Headly, Phineas C. (Box 92, Folder 26)
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth (Box 92, Folder 27)
    - Hilder, Howard (Box 92, Folder 28-31)
    - Hoar, Mary (Box 92, Folder 32)
    - Hoit-Holland, Alice May (Box 92, Folder 33)
    - Holland, Rev. W. J. (Box 92, Folder 34)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 92, Folder 35)
    - Howe, Julia Ward (Box 92, Folder 36)
    - Hubbard, Elbert (Box 92, Folder 37)
    - Hudson, Mary Clemmer Ames (Box 93, Folder 38)
    - Huggins, Sir William and Lady Margaret (Box 93, Folder 39)
    - Jackson, Helen Hunt (Box 93, Folder 40)
    - James, Arthur Curtiss (Box 93, Folder 41-42)
    - James, Harriet P. (Box 93, Folder 41-42)
    - James, D. Willis (Box 93, Folder 43)
    - James, George Wharton (Box 93, Folder 44)
    - Jeans, Sir James (Box 93, Folder 45)
    - Kennan, Mr. and Mrs. George (Box 93, Folder 46)
    - Kin, Yamei (Box 93, Folder 47)
    - Lathrop, George Parsons (Box 93, Folder 48)
    - Longyear, John M. (Box 93, Folder 49)
    - Lowell, Amy (Box 93, Folder 50)
    - Lyman, Rev. Albert Josiah (Box 93, Folder 51)
    - M (Box 93, Folder 52)
    - Munroe, Kirk (Box 93, Folder 53)
    - Munroe, (1) Mrs. K. (Mary B.) (Box 93, Folder 53)
    - Munroe, (2) Mrs. K. (Mabel S. N.) (Box 93, Folder 53)
    - Newcomb, Prof. and Mrs. Simon (Box 93, Folder 54)
    - Oumiroff and Spravka (Box 93, Folder 55)
    - P-R (Box 93, Folder 56)
    - Palmer, Alice Freeman (Box 93, Folder 57)
    - Ross-Brown, Admiral Albert (Box 93, Folder 58)
    - S (Box 93, Folder 59)
    - Schober, William Bush (Box 93, Folder 60)
    - Seligman, Isaiah (Box 93, Folder 61)
    - Shaw, Linus H. (Box 93, Folder 62)
    - Shoemaker, W. L. (Box 93, Folder 63)
    - Stearns, Alfred Ernst (Box 93, Folder 64)
    - Stearns, Mary Emeline Kittredge (Box 93, Folder 65)
    - Stearns, Olive Coit (Box 93, Folder 65)
    - Sumner, Charles (Box 93, Folder 66)
    - T (Box 93, Folder 67)
    - Thoreau family (Box 93, Folder 68)
    - Todd, David Peck (Box 93, Folder 69)
    - W-Z (Box 93, Folder 70)
    - Ward, Herbert A. (Box 93, Folder 71)
    - Ward, Lydia Avery Coonley (Box 93, Folder 71)
    - Webb, James Augustus (Box 93, Folder 72)
    - Whiting, Lilian (Box 93, Folder 73)
    - Willson, Rev. Edmund Burke (Box 93, Folder 74)
    - Unidentified persons (Box 93, Folder 75)
  - William Austin Dickinson
    - Letters of William Austin Dickinson To Mabel Loomis Todd
      - 1882 (Box 94, Folder 76)
      - 1883 February-April (Box 94, Folder 77)
      - 1883 July-August (Box 94, Folder 78)
      - 1883 November-December (Box 94, Folder 79)
      - 1883 (Box 94, Folder 80-82)
      - 1884 January-March (Box 94, Folder 83)
      - 1884 May-August (Box 94, Folder 84)
      - 1884 (Box 94, Folder 85-89)
      - 1885 April-June (Box 94, Folder 90)
      - 1885 July 3-12 (Box 94, Folder 91)
      - 1885 July 23-31 (Box 94, Folder 92)
      - 1885 August (Box 94, Folder 93)
      - 1885 August-Sep, December (Box 94, Folder 94)
      - 1885 (Box 94, Folder 95-96)
      - Re: Emily Dickinson's illness, 1886 (Box 94, Folder 97)
      - 1886 Mar, June (Box 94, Folder 98)
      - 1886 July 7-14 (Box 95, Folder 99)
      - 1886 July 15-26 (Box 95, Folder 100)
      - 1886 September 3-6 (Box 95, Folder 101)
      - 1886 (Box 95, Folder 102)
      - 1887 June (Box 95, Folder 103)
      - 1887 July (Box 95, Folder 104)
      - 1887 August (Box 95, Folder 105)
      - 1887 September 30-November 5 (Box 95, Folder 106)
      - 1887 November 7-18 (Box 95, Folder 107)
      - 1887 November 20-December 28 (Box 95, Folder 108)
      - 1887 (Box 95, Folder 109)
      - 1888 March-July (Box 95, Folder 110)
      - 1888 September-November (Box 95, Folder 111)
      - 1888 (Box 95, Folder 112-114)
      - 1889 January 3-April 10 (Box 95, Folder 115)
      - 1889 April 11-August 1 (Box 95, Folder 116)
      - 1889 August 2-13 (Box 95, Folder 117)
      - 1889 September-October (Box 96, Folder 118)
      - 1889 November (Box 96, Folder 119)
      - 1889 December (Box 96, Folder 120-121)
      - [1889?] (Box 96, Folder 122)
      - 1890 January 1-15 (Box 96, Folder 123)
      - 1890 January 16-31 (Box 96, Folder 124)
      - 1890 February 4-15 (Box 96, Folder 125)
      - 1890 February 16-27 (Box 96, Folder 126)
      - 1890 March 2-18 (Box 96, Folder 127)
      - 1890 March 20-24 (Box 96, Folder 128)
      - 1890 March 27-29 (Box 96, Folder 129)
      - 1890 April 3-11 (Box 96, Folder 130)
      - 1890 April 14-21 (Box 96, Folder 131)
      - 1890 April 24-30 (Box 96, Folder 132)
      - 1890 May (Box 96, Folder 133)
      - 1890 July-August (Box 96, Folder 134)
      - 1890 Sep, November (Box 96, Folder 135)
      - 1891 January-Mar, May (Box 96, Folder 136)
      - 1891 September 4-15 (Box 96, Folder 137)
      - 1891 September 18-21, December 23 (Box 96, Folder 138)
      - 1891 (Box 96, Folder 139)
      - 1892 February-April (Box 97, Folder 140)
      - 1892 July (Box 97, Folder 141)
      - 1892 August-November (Box 97, Folder 142)
      - 1892 (Box 97, Folder 143)
      - 1893 Feb, Apr, Aug, Oct, December (Box 97, Folder 144)
      - 1893 July 1-9 (Box 97, Folder 145)
      - 1893 July 15-21 (Box 97, Folder 146)
      - 1894 February-March (Box 97, Folder 147)
      - 1894 April-May (Box 97, Folder 148)
      - 1894 December (Box 97, Folder 149)
      - 1895 (Box 97, Folder 150)
      - Undated (Box 97, Folder 151-153)
    - Envelopes addressed to Mabel Loomis Todd, Undated (Box 97, Folder 154)
    - Letter of William Austin Dickinson to Mrs. Loomis, Undated (Box 97, Folder 155)
    - Letter of William Austin Dickinson to Merrill E. Gates [in Mabel Loomis Todd's hand], 1890 September 15 (Box 97, Folder 156)
    - Letter of William Austin Dickinson to J. Clark, 1893 August 8 (Box 97, Folder 157)
    - Letter of William Austin Dickinson to Mr. Clapp, 1894 (Box 97, Folder 158)
    - Letter of William Austin Dickinson to Clara Newman Clark, 1885 (Box 97, Folder 159)
    - Letters of William Austin Dickinson to an unidentified person, re: Emily Dickinson's letters, 1889-1892 (Box 97, Folder 160)
    - Letters of William Austin Dickinson to David Peck Todd
      - 1882 (Box 97, Folder 161)
      - 1883 (Box 97, Folder 162)
      - 1884-1889 (Box 97, Folder 163)
      - 1891-1895 (Box 97, Folder 164)
      - Undated (Box 97, Folder 165)
    - Letter of Susan Gilbert Dickinson to William Austin Dickinson, 1888 (Box 97, Folder 166)
    - Incoming correspondence to William Austin Dickinson, 1884-1885, undated (Box 97, Folder 167)
    - Letters of Mabel Loomis Todd to William Austin Dickinson
      - 1882 Feb, October (Box 98, Folder 168)
      - 1882 November (Box 98, Folder 169)
      - 1882 December (Box 98, Folder 170)
      - 1883 January-February (Box 98, Folder 171)
      - 1883 September-November (Box 98, Folder 172)
      - 1883 (Box 98, Folder 173)
      - 1884 (Box 98, Folder 174)
      - 1885 February-June (Box 98, Folder 175)
      - 1885 July (Box 98, Folder 176)
      - 1885 August (Box 98, Folder 177)
      - 1885 October-December (Box 98, Folder 178)
      - 1885 (Box 98, Folder 179-180)
      - 1886 January-February (Box 98, Folder 181)
      - 1886 March-April (Box 98, Folder 182)
      - 1886 May-June (Box 98, Folder 183)
      - 1886 July 7-14 (Box 98, Folder 184)
      - 1886 July 16-August 26 (Box 98, Folder 185)
      - 1886 September-December (Box 98, Folder 186)
      - 1886 (Box 98, Folder 187)
      - 1887 January-May (Box 98, Folder 188)
      - 1887 June 5-11 (Box 98, Folder 189)
      - 1887 June 14-23 (Box 98, Folder 190)
      - 1887 July (Box 98, Folder 191)
      - 1887 August-September (Box 98, Folder 192)
      - 1887 October-December (Box 98, Folder 193)
      - 1887 (Box 98, Folder 194)
      - 1888 January-July (Box 98, Folder 195)
      - 1888 September (Box 99, Folder 196)
      - 1888 November-Dec, undated (Box 99, Folder 197)
      - 1889 January (Box 99, Folder 198)
      - 1889 April (Box 99, Folder 199)
      - 1889 July-September (Box 99, Folder 200)
      - 1889 October (Box 99, Folder 201)
      - 1889 November 2-10 (Box 99, Folder 202)
      - 1889 November 16-30 (Box 99, Folder 203)
      - 1889 December 4-15 (Box 99, Folder 204)
      - 1889 December 20-29 (Box 99, Folder 205)
      - 1889 (Box 99, Folder 206)
      - 1890 January [pre-dated by MLT] (Box 99, Folder 207)
      - 1890 February [pre-dated by MLT] (Box 99, Folder 208)
      - 1890 March [pre-dated by MLT] (Box 99, Folder 209)
      - 1890 January (Box 99, Folder 210)
      - 1890 February 1-9 (Box 99, Folder 211)
      - 1890 February 14-28 (Box 99, Folder 212)
      - 1890 March 3-15 (Box 99, Folder 213)
      - 1890 March 19-30 (Box 99, Folder 214)
      - 1890 April 1-16 (Box 99, Folder 215)
      - 1890 April 18-30 (Box 99, Folder 216)
      - 1890 May (Box 99, Folder 217)
      - 1890 September (Box 99, Folder 218)
      - 1890 November-December (Box 100, Folder 219)
      - 1891 January-February (Box 100, Folder 220)
      - 1891 September-October (Box 100, Folder 221)
      - 1891 (Box 100, Folder 222)
      - 1892 January-February (Box 100, Folder 223)
      - 1892 Apr, July-August (Box 100, Folder 224)
      - 1892 (Box 100, Folder 225)
      - 1893 July (Box 100, Folder 226)
      - 1893 Aug, Oct, December (Box 100, Folder 227)
      - 1893 (Box 101, Folder 228)
      - 1894 January-February (Box 101, Folder 229)
      - 1894 March-April (Box 101, Folder 230)
      - 1894 May, Jul, November (Box 101, Folder 231)
      - 1895 January-July (Box 101, Folder 232)
      - 1895 August (Box 101, Folder 233)
      - Undated (Box 101, Folder 234)
    - Letters of Lavinia Dickinson to Mabel Loomis Todd, Undated (Box 101, Folder 235)
    - Envelopes addressed to William Austin Dickinson, Undated (Box 101, Folder 236)
    - Richard Sewall's notes on the William Austin Dickinson-Mabel Loomis Todd correspondence, [1970s?] (Box 101, Folder 237)
    - Bianchi, Martha Dickinson: clippings and printed matter, 1931 (Box 101, Folder 238)
    - Dickinson Trial of 1898
      - Official transcripts, 1898 (Box 101, Folder 239)
      - Mabel Loomis Todd holograph summary, typed copy with notes by Millicent Todd Bingham, 1898 (Box 101, Folder 240)
      - Newspaper accounts, 1898 (Box 101, Folder 241)
      - Essay: "Mabel Loomis Todd Speaks", 1931 October (Box 101, Folder 242)
    - William Austin Dickinson's diary
      - 1880 (Box 101, Folder 243)
      - 1882 (Box 101, Folder 244)
      - 1883 (Box 101, Folder 245)
      - 1884 (Box 102, Folder 246)
      - 1886 (Box 102, Folder 247)
    - Deed: William Austin Dickinson's sale of land to the Todds, 1886 (Box 102, Folder 248)
    - William Austin Dickinson's will, 1887 (Box 102, Folder 249)
    - Mortgage deed for the "Dell" drafted by William Austin Dickinson, 1887 June 7 (Box 102, Folder 250)
    - William Austin Dickinson's diary
      - 1888 (Box 102, Folder 251)
      - 1889 (Box 102, Folder 252)
      - 1890 (Box 102, Folder 253)
    - Description of William Austin Dickinson's diaries by Millicent Todd Bingham, Undated (Box 102, Folder 254)
    - Notes by William Austin Dickinson, Undated (Box 102, Folder 255)
    - William Austin Dickinson's criticism of the History of Amherst, Undated (Box 102, Folder 256)
    - William Austin Dickinson on Emily Dickinson's poems, Undated (Box 103, Folder 257)
    - Notes by William Austin Dickinson on the trustees' vote, Undated (Box 103, Folder 258)
    - William Austin Dickinson's statements to Mabel Loomis Todd in regard to Sue Dickinson, Undated (Box 103, Folder 259)
    - William Austin Dickinson's receipts and financial notes, 1884-1886, 1893 (Box 103, Folder 260)
    - William Austin Dickinson's printed matter, Undated (Box 103, Folder 261)
    - Photograph of Mabel Loomis Todd with the signature "Mabel Loomis Dickinson", Undated (Box 103, Folder 262)
    - Essay: "The Evolution of a Style", [1890-1896?] (Box 103, Folder 263)
    - Poems by Mattie Dickinson copied by Mabel Loomis Todd, 1892 (Box 103, Folder 264)
    - Essay: "New Year's Eve, 1900" (Box 103, Folder 265)
    - Mabel Loomis Todd's reminiscences on Emily Dickinson, 1924, undated (Box 103, Folder 266)
    - William Austin Dickinson's life and miscellaneous dates compiled by Mabel Loomis Todd, Undated (Box 103, Folder 267)
    - Notebook: "Emily", Undated (Box 103, Folder 268)
    - "Mama's Early Diary", Undated (Box 103, Folder 269)
    - Essay: "Famous Lovers," excerpts of William Austin Dickinson's letters to Mabel Loomis Todd, Undated (Box 103, Folder 270)
    - Notes by Richard B. Sewall on Mabel Loomis Todd's journal, [1970s?] (Box 103, Folder 271-272)
    - Richard B. Sewall's digest of Mabel Loomis Todd's diaries, [1970s?] (Box 103, Folder 273)
    - Locks of hair belonging to Mabel Loomis Todd and William Austin Dickinson, Undated (Box 103, Folder 274)
  - Clubs
    - The American Boy Scout
      - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 104, Folder 275)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1910 (Box 104, Folder 276)